<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>wyrmsun.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0</project_license>
  <name>Wyrmsun</name>
  <summary>Strategy game based on history, mythology and fiction</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      In the Wyrmsun universe a myriad of inhabited planets exist. Humans dwell on Earth, while dwarves inhabit Nidavellir and elves nourish the world of Alfheim. These peoples struggle to carve a place for themselves with their tools of stone, bronze and iron. And perhaps one day they will meet one another, beyond the stars...
    </p>
    <p>
      Features:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Retro-style graphics</li>
      <li>2 playable civilizations, and a number of non-playable ones</li>
      <li>23 quests to play, earning technology points which can be used to obtain new units, buildings and technologies</li>
      <li>Dozens of units, buildings and technologies</li>
      <li>Personal names and traits for units</li>
      <li>Units can earn experience, being able to upgrade to new unit types or acquire new abilities upon level-up</li>
      <li>Persistent heroes, who carry over their level and abilities throughout scenarios</li>
      <li>Possibility to create your own custom persistent heroes</li>
      <li>Normal, magic-enchanted and unique items drop from enemies</li>
      <li>Cave, Conifer Forest, Dungeon, Fairlimbed Forest and Swamp tilesets</li>
      <li>Dozens of maps of real and fictional locations to choose from, as well as random maps</li>
      <li>Living environment, with fauna reproduction and predation</li>
      <li>Very moddable game, with mod-loading capability built in</li>
      <li>Grand strategy mode, where production is resolved on the strategic (world map) level, while battles are resolved on the tactical level</li>
      <li>In-game encyclopedia, allowing players to learn more about the units, buildings and other elements of the game, as well as their historical and mythological sources of inspiration</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://andrettin.github.io/screenshots/screen_dwarven_settlement.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://andrettin.github.io/screenshots/screen_grain_farm.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <url type="homepage">https://andrettin.github.io/</url>
</component>
